SRAS. The Security Robot Automation System.
Powered by NVIDIA Cosmos Reason2.
A hundred and two million dollars.
That's how much disappeared from the Louvre in under four minutes.
October 2025. Four thieves. Eight crown jewels. Gone.
Thirty-nine percent camera coverage. A guard looking the wrong way.
No AI. No robot. No second chance.
What if the museum had a brain that never sleeps,
and a body that can go anywhere a guard can't?
SRAS combines every fixed camera in the building
with a Unitree Go2 mobile robot —
all reasoning in real time through NVIDIA Cosmos Reason2.
Five layers: raw sensors, perception, reasoning, planning, human dashboard.
The robot acts. The human stays in control.
We call this Human-Over-The-Loop.
Always informed. Always able to intervene.
The machine works. The human decides.
Here's how it flows in real life.
A blind spot is flagged. Cosmos reasons about the threat.
The planner scores priority and dispatches the robot.
On arrival, Cosmos analyzes the scene and alerts the operator.
Zero human steps needed — until the moment they matter.
We didn't just trust the model. We tested it.
Ninety-three scenarios. Twenty-three images. Three live videos.
This is what Cosmos Reason2 actually does under pressure.
Scene understanding and person detection: four out of five.
First token in a hundred and eighty-one milliseconds.
That's fast enough for real security.
Critical finding: turn on deep reasoning — and person detection drops.
More thinking. More false positives.
Our tiered setup — two-B plus eight-B — solves this at sixty dollars a day.
Ninety-seven point six percent cheaper than cloud VLMs.
Three ceiling cameras. One map frame.
When a person walks in, SRAS doesn't just see them —
it triangulates exactly where they are.
The detection buffer watches four state transitions:
new class, sustained presence, position shift, disappeared.
Nothing slips through untracked.
Meanwhile, the robot's own camera has already mapped the floor.
Fifty-three objects. Thirty-seven classes.
Paintings, doors, fire extinguishers — the planner knows every asset in the building.
Every alert gets a priority score.
Severity, confidence, recency, asset value — multiplied together.
Low scores auto-approve and resolve silently.
High scores go straight to the operator.
The robot never wastes a second on a shadow.
When the threat is real, Cosmos assigns the right robot to the right job.
The quadruped pursues. The humanoid blocks the exit.
Each matched to what it does best.
Every task moves through a gated lifecycle:
queued, dispatched, active, succeeded.
The operator can approve, pause, or cancel at any point.
Full control. Full audit trail. Nothing happens without a decision.
Now here's the hard part. Cold smoke blinds cameras.
Standard thermal detection of people through smoke: fifty-three percent.
That's barely better than a guess.
We trained a custom LoRA adapter.
A hundred and sixty-four real thermal images.
Twenty minutes of training. Thirty cents.
New result: ninety-six point two percent.
Zero false positives on smoke-only scenes.
People hidden inside smoke — went from fifty-five to ninety-one percent.
That's not a fine-tune. That's a transformation.
For thirty cents.
Everything feeds into a single command center.
Live camera feeds over WebRTC.
A 2D map tracking every robot in real time.
A full 3D view from RViz — LiDAR, TF frames, robot position.
Every alert carries the Cosmos reasoning that triggered it.
Approve, cancel, pause — or let the system run.
Cosmos isn't one model. It's a platform you extend.
Ninety-six point two percent smoke detection.
Trained in twenty minutes for thirty cents.
Ninety-seven point six percent cheaper than the cloud.
Cosmos sees. Cosmos reasons. Robots act. Humans decide.
We are DataPilot.